earthclinic.com 2017-08-30

# Earth Clinic's Privacy Notice

The privacy of our visitors to the Earth Clinic web site, [www.earthclinic.com](http://www.earthclinic.com/) ("Earth Clinic, LLC") and the users of software applications developed by Earth Clinic and used by the users of mobile devices is important to us. Because we gather certain types of information about our users, we want to help you understand the terms and conditions surrounding the collection and use of that information. This privacy statement discloses the types of information we gather, how we use it, and how to correct or change it. These privacy practices apply to the Web site that you were viewing when you clicked through to this policy, which is operated directly by us, and also apply to your access to the Web site by a mobile device or by Earth Clinic software applications running on a mobile device, except to any terms of the End User License Agreement (the “EULA”) for any Earth Clinic mobile device software application conflict with this policy, the terms of the EULA shall control.

Here is information on what types of personal information we receive and collect when you use visit the Earth Clinic LLC web sites or use Earth Clinic software applications and how we safeguard your information. We never sell your personal information to third parties.

**1\. What Information Does Earth Clinic, LLC collect?**

Our primary goal in collecting personal information is to provide you with the best and most useful content and services. Several of the services and features that we offer on our sites and our applications require you to provide us with information as a condition of usage. These include access to email newsletters and participation in our forum.

We collect personally identifiable information, such as your first name, city, state, country and email address, when you provide it to us. From time to time, we may also collect other sensitive information such as your username and password.

Once you register with one of our Earth Clinic LLC sites or through an Earth Clinic software application you are no longer anonymous to us.

**2\. Log Files and Mobile Device Information**

As with most other websites, we collect and use the data contained in log files. The information in the log files include your IP (internet protocol) address, your ISP (internet service provider, such as AOL or Shaw Cable), the browser you used to visit our site (such as Internet Explorer or Chrome), the time you visited our site and which pages you visited throughout our site.  In addition, Earth Clinic software applications may collect certain information automatically including, but not limited to, the type of mobile device you use, your mobile devices unique device ID, the IP address of your mobile device, your mobile operating system, the type of mobile internet browser you use, and information about how you use the Earth Clinic application(s). Earth Clinic does not collect precise information about the location of your mobile device.

**3\. Cookies and Web Beacons**

We do use cookies to store information, such as your personal preferences when you visit our site. This could include only showing you a popup once in your visit, or the ability to login to some of our features, such as forums.

We also use third party advertisements on earthclinic.com to support our site. Some of these advertisers may use technology such as cookies and web beacons when they advertise on our site, which will also send these advertisers (such as Google through the Google AdWords and/or AdSense programs) information including your IP address, your ISP, the browser you used to visit our site, and in some cases, whether you have Flash installed. This is generally used for geo-targeting purposes (showing New York real estate ads to someone in New York, for example) or showing certain ads based on specific sites visited (such as showing cooking ads to someone who frequents cooking sites).

This website and EarthClinic applications also use Google Analytics and/or Google Analytics for Mobile Apps which are implemented by Google Analytics Tracking Code (called page tags) which run in the client’s browser and allows us to track and report on website traffic and application usage which may include, among other things, page and application usage, where a site visitor came from, how long the visitor stayed, as well as general geographical position.

You can chose to disable or selectively turn off our cookies or third-party cookies in your browser settings, or by managing preferences in programs such as Norton Internet Security. However, this can affect how you are able to interact with our site (as well as other websites) and with EarthClinic applications. This could include the inability to login to services or programs, such as logging into forums or accounts.

**4.   Third party access to information obtained by or supplied to Earth Clinic applications**

Earth Clinic may periodically transmit aggregated, anonymized data to help us improve the our applications and our service. We will share your information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy statement.

We may disclose personally identifiable information:

  1. as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process;
  2. when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request;
  3. and/or with our trusted services providers who work on our behalf, do not have an independent use of the information we disclose to them, and have agreed to adhere to the rules set forth in this privacy statement.

**5\. Your Options**

Users who would rather not provide any of the user data requested by our registration process do not need to register with us. You can still view much of the content and use many of the services offered by our sites without registering. If you have already registered with us and wish to have your account deleted, you may do so in the member-services area of your account.  If you do not register as a user of an Earth Clinic software application, you may not be able to use some or all of the features offered by the applications until such time as you register with us.  You can stop all collection of information by Earth Clinic software applications by uninstalling the application from your computer and/or mobile devices.

**6\. Reviewing and updating your personally identifiable information**

You can review, correct, or change the information collected during registration for any of our sites. The instructions for doing this can be found in our member-services areas. Users may change information at any time and as often as necessary. Users who are experiencing problems with our services or who have questions about how our services work can contact us using the e-mail address at the bottom of this page.

**7\. Privacy Policy Changes**

Our privacy policy may be updated from time to time in our discretion and for any reason.  Any modifications to our privacy practices will be reflected first within this area of our Web site(s). If there is a material change in our privacy practices, we will indicate on our sites that our privacy practices have changed and provide a link to the new privacy statement. If we are going to be using the information collected from users in a manner materially different from that stated at the time of collection, we will send affected users written notice of the change by e-mail.

**8\. Privacy of Children**

None of the sites within our network is directed to children under the age of 13. We operate our network of sites in compliance with the [Children's Online Privacy Protection Act](http://www.ftc.gov/ogc/coppa1.htm) and do not permit registration by, and will not knowingly collect or use personally identifiable information from, anyone under 13 years of age. This requirement is clearly posted during the registration process.

**9\. Security**

We are concerned about safeguarding the confidentiality of your information. We provide physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect information we process and maintain. For example, we limit access to this information to authorized employees and contractors who need to know that information in order to operate, develop or improve our website and software applications. Please be aware that, although we endeavor provide reasonable security for information we process and maintain, no security system can prevent all potential security breaches.

**10.Your Consent**

By accessing this site, by downloading and/or using an Earth Clinic application, and/or by indicating your consent in order to gain access to the site or to access an Earth Clinic application, you are consenting to our processing of your information as set forth in this Privacy Policy now and as amended by us. "Processing” means using cookies on a computer/hand held device or using or gathering information in any way including, but not limited to, collecting, storing, deleting, using, combining and disclosing information as set forth in this Privacy Policy.

**Questions, Comments**  
Questions about this privacy statement should be sent to:  
Email: Contact Us Form

We read every message submitted and try to reply promptly to every one.
